ffwd.com 2008-12-18

# ffwd | privacy

This Privacy Policy was last modified on September 7, 2008.

RECENT UPDATES TO THESE TERMS OF USE

Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy and how we protect you.

## what this privacy policy covers

This policy explains what information of yours ffwd collects when you use the ffwd.com website and related services (the “ _Service_ ”), how ffwd uses that information and how you can control the collection, correction and/or deletion of that information. Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, email address, or phone number, and that is not otherwise publicly available, and may include information related to your past use of ffwd products and services. This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that ffwd does not own or control, or to people that ffwd does not employ or manage.

### information collection and use

1\. General

  * ffwd collects personal information when you register with ffwd, when you use ffwd products or services, when you visit ffwd pages or the pages of certain ffwd partners. ffwd may combine information about you that we have with information we obtain from business partners or other companies. 
  * When you register we may ask for information such as your name, email address, birth date, gender, zip code, occupation, industry and personal interests. Once you register with ffwd and sign in to our services, you are not anonymous to us. 
  * Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, ffwd does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number or email address. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at www.ffwd.com/privacy. 
  * ffwd automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, ffwd cookie information and the pages and products you requested. All browser activity reporting is done anonymously. 
  * ffwd uses information for the following general purposes: to operate, maintain and provide to you the features and functionality of the Service, to customize the content you see, fulfill your requests for products and services, improve our services, contact you, conduct research and provide anonymous reporting for internal and external clients. 
  * Any personal information or content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Service (for instance, in User Content you post) becomes available to the public. If you remove User Content, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other users have copied or stored your User Content.

2\. Information Sharing and Disclosure

ffwd does not rent, sell, or share personal information about you with other people or nonaffiliated companies except to provide products or services you have requested, when we have your permission, or under the following circumstances:

  * We provide the information to trusted partners who work on behalf of or with ffwd under confidentiality agreements. These companies may use your personal information to help ffwd communicate with you about offers from ffwd and our marketing partners. However, unless you have granted permission, these companies do not have any independent right to share this information. 
  * We respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. 
  * We believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of ffwd's Terms of Use or as otherwise required by law. 
  * We may transfer information about you if ffwd is acquired by or merged with another company or if we sell some or all of our assets. We will post a notice on our site before this occurs and/or if a new privacy policy will be applicable as a result. 
  * ffwd works with vendors, partners, advertisers and other service providers. In order to bring you the products and services you have requested, we may share your personal information with them. We will not authorize these service providers to share your information other than as necessary to provide the services you have requested or beyond the extent to which you have granted us permission to do so. 
  * ffwd may display targeted advertisements based on personal information. 

### cookies, web beacons, and shared objects

  * ffwd may set and access cookies on your computer. A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that is transferred from a website to the hard drive of your computer so that the site administrator may identify your computer and passively track its activities on the website. This unique number identifies your web browser to our computer system. A cookie will not allow a website to learn any personally identifiable information (such as your real name and address) that you have not otherwise disclosed. Cookies allow us to automatically remember your web browser when you visit our sites or Service. The use of cookies is an industry standard, and they are currently used on most major websites. It is possible to adjust your Web browser preferences to alert you when a cookie is sent to your hard drive, or to refuse cookies altogether. While we do not require you to use cookies, keep in mind that certain sites and services will not function properly if you set your browser to refuse all cookies. 
  * Web beacons, also known as clear GIFs or single-pixel GIFs, are small image files that we may place on Web pages and within certain email. Working in conjunction with cookies, Web beacons allow us to accurately count the number of unique users who have visited a specific page and the number of times those pages are displayed. We can also use Web beacons to let us know how many people opened certain types of email. This information is only collected in aggregate form and will not be linked to your personally identifiable information. Keep in mind that any image file on a Web page can act as a Web beacon. Third-party advertisers may use Web beacons in their advertisements. 
  * Shared Objects are used to store data on your computer in much the same way that data is stored in a cookie created through a web browser. Various uses of Shared Objects include remembering a user's favorite color, or the last frame of a movie watched. The data can only be read by movies originating from the same domain that created the Shared Object. Shared Objects can not remember a user's e-mail address or other personal information unless they willingly provide such information. 
  * Without cookies, Web beacons, and Shared Objects, it would be difficult for us to know which services have a larger audience than others, or to offer you all the services and functionality that we do. Tracking audience size helps us to better understand when to launch new services and enhance the current offerings. 
  * ffwd lets other companies that show advertisements on some of our pages or offer you products and services in connection with the ffwd service set and access their cookies on your computer. Other companies' use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. Advertisers or other companies do not have access to ffwd's cookies. 

### your ability to edit and delete your account information and preferences

  * You can edit your ffwd account information, including your e-mail notification preferences, at any time by viewing your User Profile Preferences. New categories of e-mail announcements and marketing messages may be added to the User Profile Preferences page from time to time. Users who visit this page can opt out of receiving future communications from us, and they can unsubscribe by following instructions contained in the messages they receive. We reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to the ffwd service, such as service announcements or administrative messages, without offering you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving them. 
  * You can request to permanently delete your ffwd account by contacting ffwd technical support: [support@ffwd.com](mailto:support@ffwd.com). 

### how we protect your information

  * ffwd uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to ffwd and you do so at your own risk. We may store personal information in locations outside of our direct control (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers). 
  * To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your email communications from ffwd at all times.

### compromise of personal information

In the event that personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, ffwd will promptly notify those persons whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

### links to other websites

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our website nor the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from our website to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including those that have a link on our website, is subject to that website's own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

### changes to this privacy policy

If we change our privacy policies and procedures we will post those changes on our website, and we may also notify you about significant changes by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your ffwd account.

### contact us

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about our privacy policy, please contact us:

ffwd privacy  
580 Howard St. Suite 302  
San Francisco, CA 94105  

### Updates
